Basic Nature and Purpose of PFSS
Welcome to this session.
We’re going to be looking at a concept called PFSS,
Processing for Six Sigma.
What does processing for Six Sigma mean? Well to begin to understand this.
Let's start with a simple process.
I'm going to say we've got process operation 1, which feeds operation 2,
which feeds operation 3 and so on,
till ultimately a product or service is created.
Well, this process operation 1 has a certain outcome.
I'm going to call it for the sake of argument, a deliverable.
So, what comes out of here is a deliverable. And we're going to blow that out right here.
And look at that deliverable as a simple square.
That's our deliverable.
Now, the deliverable coming out of here.
This deliverable went into operation 1. Had further processing done to it.
In other words, value added activity occurred at operation 1.
That transformed this deliverable say from a state
like this, to this state.
And I’m going to graphically illustrate that a little bit more,
just to kind of help us understand it.
As if it was a building block. Say, this is what we put in.
And this is what we got out.
So, you can see the green area has increased
and now the dashed line has become a solid line.
So the purpose of operation 1, was to add value.
Increase the green area and make it a solid line.
So, that operation did that. In this particular case, we have now declared
two critical to quality characteristics.
So, the green is a critical to quality characteristic
and this line is a critical to quality characteristic of the product.
Now, we recognize that at this operation.
There is critical to process characteristic 1,
through critical to process characteristic N. Where N is some large number.
We further recognize that these are the knobs, and dials, and switches at this operation.
The material variables, the knowledge of the operators, all of the things that are essential
to transform the deliverable from this state,
which I'll call state A to state B. A higher value state.
So, if these things are set right. If their settings are correct.
Then we will get full entitlement as we transform in
to operation 1 and that's what we get out.
In turn, that's what's fed into operation 2,
and from that we get out
something of even a higher value state. That's what comes out.
So, we put in. We get out. We feed back in. We get back out.
And so it goes, as we progressively build.
Now, we’re going to come back and talk a little bit more about this process,
in relation to Processing for Six Sigma and what that means in just a minute.
But, right now we just want to make the fundamental point
that Y is a function of X1,…,
to the Nth variable, the Nth X, where N is some large number.
And, we recognize that some of these X’s constitute the vital few,
and others constitute the trivial many.
That if I find those vital few knobs, or as we call them CTP's.
The vital few critical to process variables, knobs, dials, and switches.
I isolate the correct settings for them. What's going to happen out here?
This is going to get better. The CTQ's is going to get better.
Which means that I get more transformational entitlement
going from state A to state B to state C.
As the process capability improves, the capability of these CTP's
and this operation to transform this input deliverable to this output deliverable.
That's what we’re talking about by Processing for Six Sigma.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.